What do you think the year-end ranges will be for both Bitcoin and ETH?
So I'm going to stay consistent.
$250,000 Bitcoin, $10,000 ETH.
Yeah. But by year-end, our target for Bitcoin is $200,000 to $250,000.
And for Ethereum, somewhere between 10 and 12,000 ETH.
Thank you, extension.
Happy to introduce you to the world's largest ETH holder,
the chairman of Bitmine, Tom Lee.
Welcome back to Bankless.
Thanks for having me. I'm glad to be back.
And we also are joined by the creator of the perpetual swap, Arthur Hayes.
Arthur, welcome back to Bankless as well.
Yo, yo, what's up?
So pretty exciting times in the market.
You guys just got finished with token 2049.
So everyone's kind of recovering and reflecting as to what went on over there.
But meanwhile, on the day of recording, we have a Bitcoin all-time high,
a new Bitcoin all-time high of $126,000.
So I just obviously have to start there.
Tom, when you see the Bitcoin all-time high price, not blowing it up,
but making meaningful chunks away, chipping away at that higher and higher price.
What do you make in the market right now?
One, I think it's good to see Bitcoin at all-time highs
as we're entering the fourth quarter and not correcting or in the 90,000 level,
because we are in that seasonally strong period.
And the Fed is easing monetary policy.
So I'd say it's good to see it all-time high because this is confirmation.
And of course, it's only early October.
And I think there's still room for upside into your end.
And Bitcoin dominance sometime around last quarter really peaked out.
And it's been down ever since.
But right now, Bitcoin is really pulling liquidity out of the market.
A lot of tokens are holding their dollar price if not going down.
So Bitcoin seems to be sucking a lot of the oxygen out of the room.
Arthur, what's your makeup?
What's your diagnosis with the current state of the market
as it relates to the Bitcoin vs tokens?
Yeah, I mean, pushing bullets.
This is how it usually goes.
Bitcoin goes first.
Yeah, it runs as well.
And then tokens do better, some tokens.
I mean, obviously, people really want to see every piece of dog shit that they bought in 2013 go up in price.
But like, yeah, there'll be some very good token price appreciations.
Hopefully ETH gets its roller coaster going on the upswing quite soon.
So I'm loving this shit.
Introducing at Frax USD, the genius aligned digital dollar from Frax.
It's a secure, stable, and fully backed by institutional grade real world assets,
cussedied by BlackRock, Superstate, and Fidelity.
It's always redeemable one-to-one, transparently audited,
and built for payments, DeFi, and banking, the best of all worlds.
At the core is FraxNet, an on-chain FinTech platform built to align with emerging
US regulatory frameworks, where you can mint, redeem, and use Frax USD with just a few clicks,
deposit USDC, send a bank wire, or tokenize treasuries,
and receive programmable digital dollars straight to your wallet.
FraxNet users benefit from the underlying return of US treasuries and earn just by using the system,
whether you're bridging, minting, or holding your Frax USD works for you.
Frax isn't just a protocol, it's a digital nation, powered by the Frax token and governed by its global communities.
Join that community and help shape FraxNet's future by going to Frax.com/r/bankless.
Frax, designed for the future of compliant digital finance.
Ethereum's Layer 2 universe is exploding with choices, but if you're looking for the best
place to park and move your tokens, make your next stop, UniChain.
First, liquidity.
UniChain hosts the most liquid Uniswap V4 deployment on any Layer 2,
giving you deeper pools for flagship pairs like ETH USDC.
More liquidity means better prices, less slippage, and smoother swaps, exactly what traders crave.
The numbers back it up. UniChain leads all Layer 2s in total value-locked for Uniswap V4.
And it's not just DEET, it's fast and fully transparent,
purpose-built to be the home base for DeFi and cross-chain liquidity.
When it comes to costs, UniChain is a no-brainer.
Transaction fees come in about 95% cheaper than Ethereum mainnet,
slashing the price of creating or accessing liquidity.
Want to stay in the loop on UniChain?
Visit unichain.org or follow @Unichain on X for all the updates.
Bit Digital, ticker BTBT, is a publicly traded ETH treasury company that combines
the two biggest meta's of our time.
Ethereum and AI Compute.
Bit Digital believes that ETH will power finance,
and AI Compute will power everything.
Bit Digital gives you direct exposure to both.
Bit Digital holds more than 150,000 ETH with
institutional grade staking and validator operations.
On top of that, the company owns roughly 73% of white fiber,
an AI infrastructure business that runs high-performance GPU data centers
that adds a meaningful exposure to the growth of AI Compute with over 27 million shares.
This is an ETH treasury backed by real operations designed to capture staking
yield today while positioning for the future of intelligent computing tomorrow.
The ticker is BTBT.
This ad is not financial advice.
Do your own research, learn more about Bit Digital and try their MNAV calculator
at bit-digital.com.
That's bit-digital.com.
Bankless is being compensated by Bit Digital for this ad.
You can find out more information by clicking the link in the show notes.
Well, ETH is one of those tokens that is actually outpacing Bitcoin at least over the last 10 days.
ETH is up just three or 4% against Bitcoin over a time period
where others haven't really been able to keep up.
The last time we had you on the show, you had 0.5% of the total ETH supply.
Bitmine had 0.5% of the total ETH supply in the treasury.
Today, you are coming back on the show at 2.25%, almost halfway to your 5% target.
How did you do that?
Because there's now a similar percentage of ETH in treasury companies
as there is in Bitcoin and Bitcoin treasury companies.
But Bitcoin had a three-year head start on ETH.
And now ETH has caught up mostly in thanks to Bitmine
and the very aggressive ETH buying that's been going on in your neck of the woods.
How did you get so much ETH so quickly?
Well, it's been 12 weeks since we started the company.
So the close of the initial pipe was July 8th.
So it's been about 12 weeks.
And Bitmine has benefited from a lot of support from the public
and from institutional investors.
That's why it's the 28th most traded stock in the stock market today.
The 28th most traded stock.
Yes.
Wow.
Yeah.
And I think today might have been top 15 in terms of trading volume.
Where is that volume coming from?
That's so much.
There's many vectors because one, the stock is widely filed in by the public.
But it's also very widely acquired and purchased by institutions
who have really helped propel Bitmine's Ethereum holdings.
And especially Kathy Woods, Arc Fonts, which were a top 10 holding for her.
And obviously she has enormous assets under management.
The stock is highly volatile.
So it's one of the, I think it's the 8th most traded options chain today.
And in fact, there's also been leveraged ETFs launched.
So there's a BM and U, which is a two times Bitmine,
that also just got options listed.
So like there's a leveraged ETF.
So I think it's giving them money away.
Let's go away.
Treat that dogshit. So let's feel liquidy because Bitmine and Microstrategy combined,
and Microstrategy is, you know, of course, the OG in crypto treasuries.
But the two of us combined is 86% of all crypto trading volume of all the hundreds
of debts in the world.
Wow.
There has been just a revitalization of energy out of at least the Ethereum
cohort of the crypto world, where before big buying came around,
there was kind of like some dark times in the Ethereum world.
What would you say about the timing of Bitmine as it came in?
And now like the Ethereum has a lot of momentum behind it.
At least the energy that asset price has a lot of momentum behind it.
The Ethereum vibe, I would say is just revitalized.
Was that how much of credit will you take, Tom?
How much timing do you think that was just lucky luck on the side of Bitmine?
What do you think about all this?
Well, you know, to me, I think there was a lot of like
pieces that fell into place in 2025 that were favorable for Ethereum.
You know, one is, of course, the new administration in the US, which is crypto friendly.
And the second is the viral adoption of stablecoins that have really driven
a huge rise in interest and activity levels on Ethereum.
The third is, I think the Ethereum foundation has made a pivot that's much more markets friendly.
And I think that that's very evident, you know, even at TOCA 2049,
you know, we spent time with the Ethereum foundation and we had that conclusion several
months ago, but it was reiterated really at our time in TOCA 2049 that, you know, they want to
build and modify Ethereum and continue to upgrade to being a way that's friendly for capital markets
and for AI. So then I'd say the fourth element is Bitmine has helped clean up the narrative around
Ethereum. And I think that so all four work contributors, I'd say, Arthur, what's your
read on on the situation, not just not just inside of Ethereum, but I want to get your
perspective with that, but that's generally. So, you know, some deaths, of course,
micro strategy has a very positive and that Bitmine has a positive M nav. But as soon as you start
to go down the chart beyond that, the M navs really have started to compress. What's your read
on just the energy behind the debt? Like won't call it a trade, but there's momentum that has
dissipated from like the long tail. What's your read on the market right now?
So, like at Mailstrom, we are an advisor of EPXI. We've traded a few pipes in EPXI,
we need one of them, a B&B one and I think in Athena one as well. So, you know, the pipe trades
initially were, you know, they look great. And then you unlock and then shift fucking
falls off a cliff. Luckily, we made money on the one pipe that we've done.
I think investors like ourselves are like looking at these charts and like,
it's not that slam dunk thing you want to trade anymore. So, I think people are doing a little bit
more circumspect about how they subscribe to some of these things. And then obviously,
as timely pointed out, this is, you know, a power law,
Pareto, what do you want to fucking call it? Situation where the top dogs take the majority of what
William Collins' average 80 trading volume and then everybody else struggles. And I think that
as we move out on the risk curve in terms of the types of corporate financing vehicles that these
things use, we're going to get some more riskier stuff, which will be fun for traders like me to
trade. Like, I love trading funky derivatives. But there's going to be some tiers at the end of this,
at the end of the story. I don't think that might be near that because they're able to raise very
simple equity, like things that are creative to their stock price and let them acquire more
ETH per share and all that kind of stuff. And I'm sure you're talking in the details.
But like, you know, all these other motherfuckers are going to be issuing like,
she's never even heard of. And it's going to be some leveraged, you know, obfuscated,
you know, bigger than me charging like 20% fees kind of bullshit. And that's going to be what blows
up in people's faces at the end of the cycle. But I love that. I love it.
Is that why you were laughing when Tom was talking about the 2X long ETF option stream?
I mean, mostly because I was an ETF guy for five years, I've launched leveraged ETFs in Asia on,
you know, various things. And when my boss showed me how to structure these things and like,
the math behind this, I was like, okay, so why would you ever trade one of these things? They're
absolutely the most dogged product ever, should never, ever, ever, ever, ever buy one of a leverage
ETF. Just go buy a features contract. Do you want leverage or two times leverage? It's just
the worst thing you could ever buy. So it's just funny that you're going to add this negative gamma
product. You're going to put some options chain on a negative gamma product. You just
completely eviscerate all your capital. But like, that's the US stock market casino and
like the first shade over here at crypto and the most dogged product exists over there. So
that's just my own pet peeve and comedy around US capital markets.
Tom, this seems to be kind of like the pretty logical conclusion of what happens when like
the crypto markets and the traditional markets touch this kind of like a God and Adam hands
touching moment where like these things finally touch and then all of a sudden let's two X long
the crypto debt ETF things with the lever trades and the option chains and we're probably going to
get a little bit over our ski tips because a that's what we do in crypto. But also anyone in
financial markets is happy to like, you know, put themselves out on the risk when there's a brand
new asset class. So it kind of makes sense that we're doing this.
The bakers are making a lot of money. Someone told me I forgot where that a large bank made
a hundred and sixty million dollars in fees. They're not a large break. Sorry, a player that would
not have been would not be known for capital markets fires. We made a hundred and sixty million
dollars in fees just from that facilitating that and the last month one fucking month.
Wow. Wow. The powers that be are making a lot of money in this and they're going to continue the
game, which is nice. Tom, should we be surprised by all of that or is this all kind of just par for
the course when something crazy like the debt world happens? I mean, you know, if if we didn't
if we ignored the last four years, then then we'd look I would probably say that I'd have a different
context. But in the last four years, it's been almost impossible for crypto to access capital
markets and and it's also been very difficult for people to even have banking relationships.
And in fact, as you know, even publicly traded banks, regulated banks, two of them were essentially
shut down by the government in the last four years. So I think 2025 is a lot of pent up capital.
We know that some of the most popular IPOs this year have actually been crypto IPOs, you know,
circle and figment and, you know, bullish. I mean, they've been very successful IPOs.
And we also know that like as a bank, the stablecoins, which are really essentially banks
are a lot more profitable than their traditional tradfi bank. You know, so a crypto native business
model is vastly more profitable with less employees. So I think that there probably is a lot of
need for for people to find exposure. But you're right, like an Arthur's like knows ETFs because
that was his world before Bitmax, you know, leverage ETFs is not the crypto industry's desire,
but it's someone who's trying to capitalize on the volatility, the issuer.
And hopefully that's not going to make this, you know, to make the process less profitable for
investors because we don't really want investors to lose money getting exposure to crypto, which,
you know, they should just generally be long. Tom Arthur, on the weekly roll up, the episode
that we record being Ryan every single Friday, we talk about the markets every single week.
And overall, my vibe, my state of the market, my play is that we got a good thing going right now.
Bitcoin has been up just incrementally for three years in a row without attracting too much froth.
There's no parabola on the Bitcoin chart. And, you know, ETH got over all time highs, but it's
not there right now. And so there's seemingly just plenty of froth. There's not in crypto.
And if we were to play out the four-year cycle, Tom, I don't know what you think about the four-year
cycle, but if we were to play out the four-year cycle, we would be topping sometime in the next
one to three months, like November, December, or January. And that's four years later than 2021.
And four years before that was 2017, the tops of the crypto market. And it's just like,
I remember both of those market cycles. It just does not seem that crazy. And so I don't know
what your attitude is. It's like the four-year cycle is dead. It's a prolonged cycle. Why are you
even bringing up the cycle word to begin with? I just want to get your read on the whole
cycle nature of the crypto markets. I'll ask this question to both of you. I'm writing an essay
that'll be published. I get finished with it this week or early next week before I leave again.
But basically, I did a market study. If there was the most popular question that I got asked,
I just made 30 fucking speeches around until 2049. What do you think of the cycle? What's your
view on the four-year cycle? Are we topping? Is this it? Is it okay? Let me go back.
I strategically believe just like what you said, I don't think we're in the four-year cycle. I think
we are in a cycle that lasts until it lasts. But okay, let's go back to think about there's been
three four-year cycles, right? 2009 to 2013, 2013 to 2017 to 2021, right? And if we take a look at,
try to make it as simple as possible and use the same chart in each three periods.
And so I took a look at Fed funds rate, effective Fed's funds rate. I created a US dollar credit
index, a proxy, which is basically just other deposits and liabilities from the banking system
in the United States and reserves at the Fed. So that'll capture quantitative easing or quantity
of tightening and it'll capture bank credit growth up or down. And then as a kicker, I said,
well, you can't talk about the United States without China because they're kind of interlocked
and they either couple of each other or go in the amount of directions. And so I just pulled a
Bloomberg credit 12 months change credit impulse index. And so if we take a look at the first cycle,
we have essentially the genesis of Bitcoin, which is, I believe, a reaction to the response of the
United States to the global financial crisis. I don't believe it's a coincidence that it was
published on the 3rd of January, 2009, right after the Bernanke announced 2022 easing,
affinity or one, TARP, all that kind of stuff, right? Have the same time, China did its part,
and they went on the largest expansion of infrastructure, credit fuel growth in its history,
and they'll see the chart. And so basically, you want the dollar credit being issued at Infinium
in 2009. That catches up with the Bitcoin price by 2013. And we get that $1,400 or $1,400, whatever
you want to call it, peak rate before MT Gox uploaded. You'll see in 2013 that credit growth
rolls over a bit. You have the Taper tantrum in the United States in mid 2013, which finally
catches up with credit growth in China. They were not growing credit as fast as they were. So the
rate of it decelerated, even though it was still growing, the second derivative was deceleration.
And so that popped the first crypto bubble. Let me move to 2017 bubble, the ICO bubble.
And in that instance, you had China leading the way where they went on a massive credit
expansion in 2015, which caused a high in the Shanghai stock market, a massive devaluation
of Yuan, obviously, 2015. And this sort of brought Bitcoin out of its toll drums. And that started
the 2017 ICO rally. But the United States is going in the opposite direction. Fed funds
was actually increasing once we get into 2017, and credit growth was falling. And so finally,
that caught up with Bitcoin, because you can't really escape the time value of money. Nobody can.
And the bubble pops in 2017 by the end of 2017. Then we get the third bubble, or whatever you're
going to call it, the COVID response. Obviously, we know what that story was all about. That was
stimulus checks in the United States. China was very circle stuck in the amount of money issue.
But again, its credit growth increased. And by late 2021, we had the Fed talking about how it was
going to reach its balance sheet, increase interest rates, due to inflation. And pretty
predictably, they quite peaked in November, right around the time when everyone expected the Fed to
start on a tightening cycle. And now we're in the current cycle. And basically,
this cycle has been about the reverse repo program, which was a two and a half trillion that
that girl, Yellen, injected into the markets, starting in 2022. And that has basically run out
until now. And so if you're a proponent of this theory of, okay, for your cycle, you say, oh, well,
you know, take a look at reverse repo at zero, there's no more liquidity. But the Fed has started
cutting rates. You have Trump and Bessam talking about how they want to run the economy hot,
which basically means either the Fed puts money, or the big sister puts money. I don't care which one,
you can listen to speeches, they'll talk about either one interchangeably. They want it used to
housing market. I don't have the charge in front of me, but it's something like trillions of dollars
of home equity that has been that's basically sitting dormant on the balance sheet of the American
public and their housing market. And Trump is going to lower mortgage rates. However, he does it,
there's very various ways to do it, to unlock that money to then go into financial markets or buy
a house, buy a car, but whatever. Trump is talking about stimulus checks, China, which has been an
essentially on and off deflation in terms of credit growth over the last few years is making
noise that they want to revitalize the housing market. Will it be as crazy as 2015? No, but it
won't be as bad as it then post COVID. So this cycle is different than the last three. If you
want to take a look at Chinese credit and US credit, which leads me to say there is no four-year cycle
at least right now. And so we are in sort of a extended cycle. We're going to call a new world
order change in three situation, whatever, right? And so I am of the opinion that this cycle ends
when the Trump administration ends, because it will be a reaction against Trump, whether you like
it or not. It doesn't really matter. And that's a 2027 story when the rhetoric of the opposing
Team Blue Democrats starts to cause questions and investors minds, what if they win? And therefore,
what if things change? Therefore, I maybe should actually take some chip off the table. So that's
my guiding light and five-minute plug for this essay that I'll come up with in a few days.
I thought that was very great. Tom, what's your read on the situation? Do you like what Arthur
just said? Is that resonating with you? Yeah, I mean, I think Arthur put it really well. I think he
kind of put a lot of pieces together for people. And maybe the only thing I'd add is two things.
One is it's very evident in sentiment because in 2017, there was a lot more exuberance in 2021,
too, both in equities and crypto. I think because of Trump and the divisiveness that he is, and also
because of the swoon we had in stocks in February to April, that sentiment still really muted. I
mean, we see that on the fun strut side. And I guess the second thing I'd add is, I think he's
spot on that crypto needs to really make overtures to both sides of the political side over the
next few years because we don't want a change in administration to result in a complete flip in
that in actually the way crypto is regulated. I mean, I think it's actually a really important
policy thing he's flagging. Yeah, we've been big proponents of that at Bankless is that crypto is
technology, not partisan. Like the internet is not partisan and neither neither should crypto be.
But also at the same time, Tom, we have as an industry made fantastic progress over the last
two years, BlackRock is aggressively into this space with their two main ETF products and their
tokenization products, which we know there's more coming down the pipe there. And of course,
that's just BlackRock. I could rattle off 20, 30, 40 more institutions that are now in crypto,
building in crypto materially that we're not in the Biden administration. So to some degree,
yes, I'm so worried about a pendulum swing in Capitol Hill, but also we're kind of embedded
in there like crypto has seized the opportunity of the Donald Trump administration to really dig
itself in protect itself and make partnerships and do BD with the existing traffic system. So to
some degree, I kind of think we're also buffered. Maybe you agree? Maybe you disagree?
Yeah, I may agree. But I think that there are probably some things that are important to like
democratic stakeholders such as UBI or social policy that I think crypto can
do some work around. I think UBI is probably functionally only enabled because we have blockchain
and the ability to validate transactions in the finality. And so I think that there is a lot that
can be appealing to non-republicans about crypto as well.
I want to turn to the conversation back to home territory for me, which is ETH and Ethereum.
Tom, you're approaching half of your target and you're almost at 2.5%. You want to get to 5%.
I think it's gone faster than anyone's expected you to get to 5. I think when even when I heard
Tom Lee wants to put 5% of ETH on Bitmine, I was like, well, sure, so do I though.
And you're halfway there. So I don't think anyone can really doubt the intentionality or
the feasibility of actually getting there. Assuming you do get to 5%, which maybe happens
this year, maybe happens next year, do you stop? What happens next?
5%, as you pointed out, was in some ways aspirational because we were just thinking about what's the
level of ETH holdings that isn't going to be disruptive to the ecosystem, but a level
that can actually allow you to have a positive benevolent influence. And so I think 5% was sort
of that waypoint. But we spent some time with other researchers and especially thinking about
the power law. I think you can, especially in a competitive dynamic, move even as high as 10%
without actually disrupting the ecosystem. And then of course, as you know, a debt is essentially
a permanent holder of ETH. So in some ways, it provides a lot of balance to the network. So I
think it's possible to go beyond 5%. But of course, we still have to get to 5%. And I don't know how
expensive it's going to be because ETH has actually cooperated because it stayed in the 4,000 range
for now. But as ETH moves up, especially in the fourth quarter, it could get very expensive to
get to 5%. What do you think, Arthur? Do you think Tom can get to 5%? Sure. I mean, if you're
able to sort of tap into the institutional pipes of money that wants to get into the dats, especially,
you know, everybody is a momentum person now regardless of what stage in the capital structure
you're especially in a traffic because everyone is trying to keep their jobs. And so how do you
keep your job? You buy the thing that went up last month. Last month, ETH is up and dats are cool.
I mean, I'm all about dats. And so I'm assuming that whatever your baker is, they're calling
off the hook, pitching all sorts of interesting things and how to raise some money from, you know,
very motivated individual clients who now all of a sudden want to do dats again,
whereas maybe two months ago, because the market was kind of sideways, they weren't so key.
Tom, with 5% plus, I mean, you're already bitmines already the number one ETH holder.
But if 5% plus it's starting, it's starting to approach structural, like a structural relationship
with Ethereum. You called a bit mine would be a ballast to Ethereum. I also noticed that you
took a photo with Vitalik lately, which I thought was great. Are you meeting people around the
Ethereum ecosystem because of the position that you have? Like, do you talk to people at the Ethereum
foundation or just other stakeholders of Ethereum? How have you found yourself just embedding yourself
into the Ethereum world? Yes, the answer is yes. You know, the Ethereum foundation has been a great
organization to dialogue with. We're very aligned with them. And Thomas has been great. We really
want to help bridge the trad fine capital markets world and their needs and the specs that they
care about to be heard properly by the ETH foundation. So I think us being a large holder
Ethereum has given us a place to be a center point of that conversation. And I think that's important.
We have been meeting with a lot of the core developers and we had a great meeting with Vitalik.
And I don't want to overuse the idea, but because bit mine has so much Ethereum, of course,
it's a source of liquidity and scale. So they overuse where it's kingmaker, but I think we can
have a role in helping shape how some of the DeFi projects that get seeded. And we can also make
selective investments with planning to use 1% of the balance sheet, which is about 130 million right
now to invest in in in projects, whether it's crypto native or traditional, like we made a small
investment in eco, which is the world coin treasury. And I think that we're increasingly viewed as
not just a debt, but kind of as digital infrastructure. But that was our thesis from the beginning that,
you know, we're providing a security function by when we stake. But that's not the only role that
a large holder Ethereum would play. And I think there's this informal role that we played, I think,
who just helping simplify and really improve the narrative around Ethereum. And I think that's also
been helpful, because that's how TreadFi can also understand, you know, as banks want to build on
the blockchain, how which layer ones that they want to work with their, you know, which organizations.
And I think we were sort of that non foundation entity that exists. Yeah, certainly, Ethereum,
naturally, because of what it is, doesn't have a very large voice, because the Ethereum foundation
has always intentionally pushed Ethereum's voice to the margins, right? Ethereum's voice is its
community, because the Ethereum Foundation doesn't want to be the voice of Ethereum. But then somebody
like Tom Lee, like Bitmine rising up and be like, well, we have a voice, it's roughly 2.25% of the
total e supply. And actually, like embodying that voice of Ethereum through the proof of the actual
ownership of ETH, but also being active, not like an active manager of the capital, as are at
least a growing the ETH ecosystem, is something that Ethereum's never really, really had before.
I'm curious, there's been murmurings or just like people using their imagination about where
Bitmine would ever potentially get involved in governance over Ethereum. And this gets into the
conversations of like all core Devs calls or actual protocol design. Do you ever see yourself
getting involved or some Bitmine person getting involved in that level of granularity of Ethereum?
Or is it more from like the advocate and liquidity and capital formation side of things?
It's a great question. You know, I think it's at best practice. It's better that, you know, Bitmine
have a more consultative view on development, you know, helping identify priorities. And I think
even acting as like a diplomat or liaison or a third party intermediary, because I think that
would play to our strengths. You know, we have a lot of connectivity to the traditional financial
world. And because we're in existing rails and operate in that side of the world, that's what would
be more of playing to the strengths of Bitmine rather than, as you're pointing out, protocol design.
You know, we don't want to stretch beyond our capabilities.
Arthur, I want to get your perspective on ETH's position as it stands in 2025 as the author of
an article that was once titled the $200 billion shit coin. Do you think, I think that was right
number? Do you think ETH ought to be comped to Bitcoin in 2025? Or should it be more comped to
the other smart contract platforms of which there are many in the crypto space? Which do you think
is the more relevant comp for Ethereum? I mean, I guess from a higher level philosophical point,
and I know you may differ me from me on this is I view ETH, I view Bitcoin as money and I view ETH
as compute. And so that's how I separate the two. And they're both very important. Obviously,
the two largest holdings in my portfolio. And so I believe ETH should be comped in that
particular way. It is the compute reference asset, if you want to call it that. And so I don't know,
what do you want to compare it to? Nvidia or Apple or whatever Amazon, like something like that,
like a tech company, right? That's kind of how I would think about ETH. When is Ethereum going to
be more valuable than Nvidia or TSMC or one of these backbones of the internet and AI and all
that kind of stuff? That's what I think ETH should aspire to. And all the other tokens can
worry about how they compare to ETH. But I think ETH needs to elevate itself above the rest of
the muck down where I play very aggressively. Tom, what do you think about that frame of
reference for ETH? Bitcoin is money. ETH is compute. How does that land with you?
Yeah. I mean, I think that they're complementary. So one is not a replacement for the other.
And in a way that's part of our framework, when we think of digital money and digital goal,
that's Bitcoin and that's already been well established. In fact, that's why many investors
will own Bitcoin. But Ethereum is an architecture that we can see Wall Street building on and AI.
And it's not that different than how in 1971, there was two forks, gold, because the dollar went
off the gold standard of gold became that store value. But then a whole economy was built around
making sure the dollar, which was now synthetic became the standard bearer. And that's what Wall
Street did. And in terms of value creation, both creative value, gold is now a $2 trillion
network value and equity, which has really came out of a synthetic dollar, right? We didn't want
us to go on to a Deutsche Mark or Yen standard. That's a $40 trillion asset. So I think both
come out of crypto, but address different markets. So I think Ethereum can grow even without having
any cannibalization or competition with Bitcoin. Imagine a world where traditional finance meets
the power of blockchain seamlessly. That's what mantle is pioneering with blockchain for banking,
a revolutionary new category at the intersection of tradfi and web3. At the heart is you are the
world's first money app built fully on chain. It gives you a Swiss I ban account blending fiat
currencies like the euro, the Swiss Franc, the United States dollar or the renminbi with crypto
all in one place. Enjoy real world usability and blockchains trust and program ability.
Transactions post directly to the blockchain compatible with tradfi rails and packed with
integrated DeFi futures. You are transforms mantle network into the ultimate platform for
on chain financial services, unifying payments, trading and assets like the MI4, the MEs protocol
and functions FBTC backed by developer grants, ecosystem incentives and top distribution through
the you are app reward stations and buy bit launch pool for mnt holders. Every economic activity in
you are drives value back to you embodying the entire stack and future growth of this super app
ecosystem. Follow mantle on X at mantle underscore official for the latest updates on blockchain
for banking that's X.com slash mantle underscore official introducing K gen AKA verify the world's
largest verified distribution protocol or VDP. If you're trying to grow a real protocol or app,
you need real users doing real actions. If it's not verify it's just noise at the core of verify
is poggy K gen's identity and reputation framework. It helps you reach humans not bought
improves what your users actually did. So your budget goes to the right people with verify you
can run verified user acquisition with confidence, keeping people coming back with retention tools
like loyalty rewards, quests and achievements and even power AI training and evaluation using
trusted verified user groups, ensuring your models learn from clean data. And when it's time to reward
your community, there's the K store, a global rewards marketplace where users can redeem perks
that connect directly back to your app. Put simply, when growth is built on real users,
you grow faster. And that's exactly what verify delivers. If you're building a web 3 AI or gaming
request a demo to grow your protocol at www dot K gen dot IO slash demo. That's www dot K G E N dot
IO slash demo. Do you think that you're one of the best traders in crypto? Now's your chance to prove
it. Bullish has launched their pro trading competition, a global challenge for professional
traders now open to us residents. This isn't leaderboard cloud, it's real capital, real strategy and
real rewards. The top three winners will each manage a one year separately managed account
funded by bullish with a total of $14 million in Bitcoin equivalent capital on the line. Winners
earn a 1% management fee plus 20% profit share subject to high watermarks. Finalists will be judged
by a panel of leading digital asset managers with recognition across strategies and regions.
Exposure to multi manager funds and quant firms and perks like access to coin desk data and indices
and consensus conference benefits. Build your legacy, seize the mandate and register today at
bullish.com slash promotions slash pro trader. That's bullish.com slash promotions slash pro
trader. There's a link in the show notes for more information. I do enjoy the comparison that
eat his compute but I'll point it towards eat his compute for banks or for financial institutions.
Like who's doing the compute? Who's consuming the compute? Financial institutions are consuming
that compute and like something that we've seen ever since we've had a more favorable regulatory
environment is these financial institutions. The more innovative ones, the more forward looking ones
are moving into this space. Again, BlackRock with the ETFs and its tokenization fund and the
other tokenization products that are coming down the line. Fidelity, many of these people then
Stripe comes in and builds their own Ethereum virtual machine blockchain. All of a sudden,
a lot of the forward looking finance category companies are now building on blockchain. I think
the broad question, Tom, for you is like playing this out into the future if we fast forward and
let this bake a little bit. Does blockchain just make the finance sector now also the tech sector?
If they're all running on tech rails to begin with, what do you think about this?
That is our theory and our thesis because I think if I took JP Morgan, for instance, and this is
something we've written about at Funstrap that they are operating and supported by 313,000
employees, but a JP Morgan built on the blockchain might only need 20,000 employees and operate with
far greater clarity and vision and efficiency. JP Morgan may end up being especially using AI
more of a tech company. They're replacing humans with tech spend and using the blockchain for
finality and security and the multiples of banks to change, going from trading at price to tangible
book to actually having a PE multiple and Kathy would has pointed this out. That's exactly what
happened with Costco and Walmart that they used to be traded like typical consumer staples 15 to
16 times earnings, but because they essentially systematized their business, Walmart and Costco
trade 35 to 50 times forward earnings. That's a higher PE multiple than Nvidia, which trades at
30 times. One of the bits of news that have come out recently is that Tether is looking to raise at
a $500 billion valuation, which if it was a crypto asset that would put it at number three
behind Bitcoin, ETH, and then Ethereum, it would be number three. Arthur, when you saw this news,
when you saw the $500 billion valuation for Tether, what was your reaction? I was like,
okay, guess I go to IPO, otherwise why they don't need money. I imagine that Giancarlo and
JL are probably up there with CZ in terms of how rich they are, who knows, because of all the
crypto they own and equity values of their other companies. But as Tom said, they're the best bank
ever created. They have 150 employees and they tend something billion dollars in net income
every year. I would much rather use Tether to pay my ski guide in Argentina or buy a product in
Southeast Asia or whatever than ever try to fucking use JP Morgan outside of New York City.
Why would you ever want to shoot yourself in a head repeatedly and survive? That's what it
feels like every time I try to use a commercial bank versus like, okay, log into my Metamask or
Phantom Wall or whatever and send somebody some money. I think obviously the emerging world gets it
and these banks are going to either have a business model like Tether, one or two of them in every
big market or they're going to be zeros. They'll fight tooth and nail the politics because that's
what a bank is. It's an extension of the local government in which they operate and they'll try
to do all sorts of things to forestall the inevitable. But we drive cars instead of driving horse and
buggy, even though the horse and buggy guys wanted to make sure they were in their cars.
And so it'll happen over time in the banks that are forward looking at the ones that'll
survive and maybe in five to 10 years time, there won't be all these thousands of banks
and everything totally around the world. There'll be one or two tech forward banks that can compete
with a FinTech or a social media company and then there will be nobody else. And that'll be great
because you can free all this amazing human intellectual capital from the treasury of working
for a dog-shit bank. Tom, the Tether $500 billion valuation, was that sticker shock to you?
That checks out? What were your thoughts? Yeah, I mean, I think it checks out because we have to
keep in mind and that's actually equity value. So it's not the value that Tether
token, but really the value of the issuer. Tether has been the central bank for crypto. I mean,
in 2017, if we go back, they were incredibly novel and ingenious. I mean, they were Bitcoin
holders, but they've proven that they're not just Bitcoin OGs. They created a business that
acted as a central bank and I think even companies or entities like being
finance, etc. wouldn't really have existed without the existence of Tether. And in the ensuing years,
Tether has actually increased its circulating supply. If you look at how much Tether has grown,
its usefulness is growing as crypto has expanded and even as crypto has become
more regulatory accepted, Tether's growth rates accelerated. So to me, I think it's pretty evident
Tether is a growth company and at $500 billion, it might actually be a bargain. I mean, we should
maybe think about the fact that Tether, when does Tether flip JP Morgan as the largest bank in the
world? And I'm not, I don't know Tether's financials, but because of how much growth they've achieved
just even in the last few years, I think we have to realize that this may be, as Arthur says,
one of the best banks in the world. When you go to CoinGecko, our favorite website to go,
just look at their market cap rankings, they put stablecoins on there, of course.
And so the stablecoin market cap of Tether is coming in at $177 billion. So it's $177
billion of Tether circulating on all the blockchains. You add them all together to $177. Bitcoin is
at $2.5 billion. Arthur, do you think that Tether, the supply of Tether, the stablecoin could ever
flip Bitcoin? Is that a realistic statement? Of course it is. I think so. I mean,
the dollars, the Tether tokenize dollars. I mean, if Buffalo Bill Besson and Trump had their way,
that would absolutely happen. And it would come at the expense of your dollar deposit,
it would come at the expense of banking every single person outside of the United States,
the dollar bank account, in opposition to their local central bank. That is exactly what they want
to happen. And they will issue as much debt as Tether or whoever else wants to acquire with
the deposit that they bring in. So I absolutely think that is possible. And that's the goal,
obviously, of the United States administration. Tom, do you agree?
I do. And then again, if we're just doing the math, so from, let's say, $200 billion
surveying supply to $2 trillion, that incremental $1.8 trillion, what value capture would Tether
have? It's enormous. I mean, this is probably why crypto equities might surprise us because they're
turning into better businesses because they're using the blockchain.
What message do you think Wall Street is hearing when they see Circle IPO and then just have
an incredible price action after that? Stripe comes in and makes a stablecoin blockchain.
Everyone is just, whoever does anything in crypto gets a 20, 30, 40% boost valuation.
The new crypto equities are popping right off the gate. What message is Wall Street hearing right
now? Control F, Control R crypto. And then S9 that you're about to produce.
Is it that simple? That's the message. And then the really smart ones will actually build a
business right. But fuck that. That's like, that takes time. Well, that makes me think of
our there is the whole Long Island blockchain. Tom, you know this story?
Yeah, that was like 2017. Yeah, we're Long Island. I see changed their name to Long Island
blockchain. And this stock pops by like it's two X in a day. And that was also the top of 2017.
I was like, it's time to be selling. I mean, today, I might say that today,
blockchains look a lot more attractive because of the security risks of centralized software
entities. I mean, I think cyber hacks are becoming so visible and companies are getting crippled,
and which is maybe raising the need and the benefits of actually having public blockchains
for finality. And maybe that's part of the hidden message. Because I think seven years ago,
even if the administration was friendly, it's not like a bunch of people would have been wanting to
issue stablecoins or build a new business on the blockchain or really show it. But I think today,
it's really in demand now. It's interesting that you say that because usually, I think when people
hear about loss of money via hacks or exploits, it's from crypto. Like some crypto protocol got
hacks and bridge got hacked. And then North Korea just found themselves $20 billion or something
like this. That's the typical story. Granted, we haven't had one of those stories in a while.
In fact, Vitalik recently wrote an article about how DeFi losses, like just capital losses inside
of DeFi is something less than 0.3% because hacks and exploits are just down so low. So,
it's interesting that you say that, Tom, because that's an inversion from what it's been historically.
If you think about the largest hack recently with the Bybit hack, right?
Yeah. I don't think it's fair to say that that's a hack of a public blockchain.
That is a hack of a safe and proper implementation of that by a centralized entity.
And so I think it goes to Tom's point. Centralized entities face these risks. The more that you can
have processes, finality, whatever you want to call it, that is completely adjudicated by
a public blockchain. Of course, yes, there are risks inherent in those blockchains.
And if you use something that's not very secure, obviously not like ETH or Bitcoin,
then you have all the civil 51 pick your sort of issues with a proof of work or proof of stake
blockchain that can happen. But the centralized company is always the risk.
And if the more things that we can have on these public blockchains are safer,
we are in crypto and in traditional finance. And that'd be amazing if that is the message that
corporate officers are receiving. I doubt that they're that subtle. I think they're more
let's just change the words in the S9 to start with. And then maybe the young kid in
the technology department can finally get some political capital to build some really cool solutions
for a stock company. Yeah. And I think if we just sum up everything from traditional financial
letters, JP Morgan, 6% of their transactions are suspicious, along with merchant fraud.
And then all the hacks that have happened to department stores and all the identity leaks,
I think it dwarfs the losses from crypto. And of course, and then Bitcoin and Ethereum have
actually, as you know, have not have any recorded history of a breach on their blockchain.
I want to knock off some last subjects here as we get into the final stages of this interview.
One of them I want to talk about is this whole emerging concept of like financial entertainment.
And I think this is kind of centered around prediction markets, but also things like pumped
up fun. So pumped up fun as a live stream platform, where you can launch a token,
and you have a stream is Twitch stream associated with it. There's a bunch of content producers
making a ton of content about poly market contracts, just will, will Taylor Swift get engaged?
And you know, not that much volume in the grand scheme of things, but a ton of content production,
just being made around that one market. Tom, I don't know if you have any thoughts or
if you've been thinking in this world, but like this whole growing attention towards
just financial entertainment on blockchain rails. What do you think about all this?
Yeah, I mean, I think financial entertainment is might even understate really how important
everything these prediction markets are doing. I mean, to me, the 2024 election and Trump
poly market and the role poly market played in calling that election tells me that it's not
just for entertainment. It's really serious wisdom of the crowd knowledge that's coming into play.
As long as these betting markets don't influence by itself, by reflexity, the outcome. But to me,
I think that that's as we move to tokenize equities and real world assets. And when you overlay that
with prediction markets, that's really the alchemy that's going to cause the financial system to
actually be a lot more liquid and for capital to be more easily. But I'm overglossing. I mean,
Arthur has a lot more interesting anecdotes about that. Yeah, I mean, the sad part is that
the inflation that has come and is to come globally around the world has created a class of
speculators and that everyone who doesn't own enough financial assets, so call 95% and 99%
of the population, your salaries ain't going to cut it. Everybody knows that intrinsically,
whether or not you can do the math or not. And so they gravitate towards the stock market,
because that's been allowed in most countries or they go to casinos or now we have crypto,
which is OK, I can take my small amount of whatever savings I've been able to accumulate.
Whatever the new hot thing is, I think crypto or pop that phone, I mean coins, I interestingly
understand, OK, just will this be popular in five minutes time versus today? I'm going to go
to trade that and then maybe I can be like that guy or that girl that I see on Instagram or TikTok
and buy my house, buy my car, pay off a bills, whatever it is, because I know in my gut that what
I'm doing right now and anything I aspire to do in the future, there is no fucking way that I'm
going to be able to afford the things that I've been told I should be able to afford, whether it's
a house, starting a family debt-free lifestyle. And that's not an American thing. It's a global
thing. And it's very sad. But that's the world that we live in and tell people farewell off all
these bullshit governments and we reform the financial system. This is going to be a state
of play. And so pump that fun, probably market, all these things that bring markets. And this is
why a lot of governments are scared because markets bring transparency, like what the people
actually want versus what they're delivering in terms of policies and services and goods,
usually are at odds. And I am a firm believer and I love free markets and I wouldn't even see the
United States as a free market economy. It's very controlled economy in various
states and every country is on a continuum on this journey. But I think markets give good signals.
And let's see what the signals give. And if the signals are that everyone is going on
pump that fun trading on, somebody taking a shit on somebody else and that's the most trending thing,
what's better than a meme coin on it, what does it tell you about the value of money and what people
will ascribe to how the governments globally have respected our dignity as human beings
and what they've created of this energy derivative of money. So I think it's a philosophical indictment
on the bankruptness of global governments that people gravitate to trade these things because
they have no other option. Wow, Arthur, that was profound. I was not ready for somebody to connect
some pumped up fun, shit coin streamer to the to the hollowness of our money supply.
It's all related. It's almost Shakespeare there.
That's close to Shakespeare, yeah. On the other side of the speculation spectrum,
Tom Arthur here, of course, invented the perpetual swap, as I'm sure you know,
is something that was birthed in crypto as just a neutral financial tool.
Do you see perps making their way going backwards into tradfi and being adopted in tradfi? Or do you
think kind of perps are just going to stick around on the future side of the financial world? I don't
know if you have a take or opinion here. I mean, we know that in the crypto world,
products have emerged and leaked into the traditional financial world and they've been
quickly adopted. I mean, stable coin is like the biggest one that really has been so widely
adopted. Yeah, I think that there are a lot of benefits to perpetual futures.
That's a little bit outside my world because I typically focus on cash settled item or even cash
traded. But without question, I think you're going to see innovation moving in both directions.
Arthur, do you think tradfi is going to adopt your beloved perps, baby?
Yeah, I mean, I know when people say traffic, I think they really mean the United States capital
markets. They're not really talking about everywhere else in the world. And I've spoken to a lot of
founders who are having some sort of iteration on a purse and they talk about, oh, I'm going to
go into the US and I think my message to all of them is I think that they're going about it.
They're not barking up the right tree. Yes, you can get some sort of license to operate some
sort of exchange in the United States. And that's not really why the CME and the CBOE and some of
these exchanges are so entrenched and powerful. It's because the clearing system in the United
States is based on an antiquated model that works for equity trading in the 1930s, right? Not in
today's right like not even any exchange does real time settlement.
Talk about the risks to CBOE and CME like these are very under capitalized institutions
relative to the volatility of products that they list and the margin they collect from the
citadels and the virtues of the world. So if any founders are saying, I'm going to take this
perk and I want to bring it to the US, I think the battle that they have to fight is how are they
going to open up the designated clearing organization licenses that are have, I don't think when it's
been awarded in 30 or 40 years, only 14 of them in the US. And so if they're able to somehow,
some way get one of those licenses and allow the socialized laws insurance fund model
to persist, then they're going to be able to issue thousand X leverage things because they're not
going to be putting their exchange at risk by using these antiquated clearing things that force
you to use the force you on board to volatility in your business model, which you otherwise wouldn't.
So I know it's a bit in the weeds, but I hope there's some, you know, perp decks founders
to be or wanting to be, you know, if that's where you're going to spend your energy attacking,
I think that's what you should attack if you really want to fuck up the US market and take the CME
down to zero, which is where they belong. Seems all very complicated. Actually, it just seems
like the simple thing to do is to just make a perp decks and not really worried about the
regulations. Yeah, you tried that once. Oh, man, Arthur, Tom, this has been great.
One last question for you guys. It is October 6. So we've got two months, three weeks before the
end of the year. Bitcoin just hit an all time high, the day of recording and 126,000 ether.
I would like it to get a lace above 5,000 this month, hopefully. Arthur, what do you think the
year end ranges will be for both Bitcoin and ETH? So I'm going to stay consistent.
$250,000 Bitcoin, $10,000 ETH. $10,000 ETH. You think ETH can do more than a doubling in two
and a half months? Yeah. All right. Tom, you dropped off really quick, but the question is,
end of year price targets. We got two months, three weeks before December 31. What do you think
ETH is going to be? What do you think Bitcoin's going to be? Yeah, but the year end, our target for
Bitcoin is $200,000 to $250,000. And for Ethereum, somewhere between 10 and 12,000 ETH.
Even higher than Arthur. So that's basically what Arthur is going to say.
I mean, if Tom says it, this is going to happen.
It's not a little bit fast, Tom. So like I said, about this last year of price action,
especially Bitcoin over the last three years, it's just been slowly incremental up. If you're
telling me ETH is going to do almost a 2.5 X in two months, to me, that is no longer incremental.
That has started to become closer to a blow off top territory, which I don't want. I want the slow,
incremental price rise for years. If it did do a 2.5 X, wouldn't you be worried about it
kind of just being a little bit too fast? I mean, as you know, Ethereum's basically been
basing for four years now, just broke out of the range. So to me, it wouldn't be a blow off top,
but rather seeking essentially price discovery at a new level. And then at a time when I think
there would be a lot of fundamental things happening next year. So I don't think it's the top,
but it is a big level, be a big level, but a happy level.
Yeah, Tom, Arthur, I don't know if I'm going to have you guys back on again by the time that
it's your wraps. But if you could think forward into 2026 and kind of just make a broad wish list
for the crypto industry goals that the crypto industry should focus on, maybe goals that
you're doing at Bitmine or Arthur, you're doing with your trading and writing, what do you want
to happen for the industry in 2026, the near term, mid term goals? Tom, I'll start with you.
For Bitmine, of course, growing its holdings and staking, but I think we would also be closer to
moving towards that phase two and phase three of the company where we would be,
you'd see us involved in some specific projects that are going to strengthen really the efforts
of Bitmine. And then for the industry, I'd love to see some innovation around the betting markets
and tokenized equities. I think that that could be a 2026 thing. Will we see a tokenized Bitmine?
I'm less incentive to tokenize Bitmine because I think what's more important is to see
tokenizing a company so that we can extract and identify the portions of value. I'd rather
see NVIDIA tokenized and then trade it as if we can own NVIDIA's China revenue streams or its
Blackwell sales and then using prediction markets to actually hedge that so we could be betting
against Fed tightening on and the implications for its margins or Blackwell sales. I think that's
really what I think is exciting about tokenization. Arthur, 2026, aspirations, goals for yourself.
Here's my macro wish list. Let's go on the list. France leaves a euro. ECB builds up euro,
billions and trillions of euros. China reflates the housing market. Dollar yen goes to 200,
BoJ capitulates and just starts printing a lot more money. And Trump takes over the Fed and goes
yield curve control. And then in terms of the crypto product landscape, I'd love to see 24/7
perps on MAG 7, big US tech stocks. I know some there's some projects working on it.
It'd be great to see that that market kick off and sort of give leverage trading in the United
States from the traditional players that run for their money and let people trade some other things.
Beautiful. Tom, Arthur, this has been great. Thanks for coming on Bankless.
Thanks for having me. Thank you. Banklessation. You guys know the deal. Crypto is risky. You
can lose what you put in. But nonetheless, we are headed west. This frontier is not for everyone,
but we're glad you're with us on the Bankless journey. Thanks a lot.